Drachman-Taylor family papers, 1875-1996
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series 3: Writings, 1914-1984
  - Subseries: Articles, 1925-1971
    - Harems are for Lady Journalists. undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - 1941 How to Entertain Without Money. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - How to Make your Secretary Love You. undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Husbands' Paradise. 1930 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - I Learned about Husbands in a Harem. 1931 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - A Lady Journalist in Morocco. undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Last Paradise for Husbands. undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Local Color. undated (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Lots of Love. undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Nobody's Mad Now. undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Not Running From, But After 'The War.' undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - On Reading. undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - One Woman and Seventeen Thousand Men. undated (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - One Woman and 17,000 Men. 1926 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - “Our” Sunday in the Desert. undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Radiographs. undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - The Seamy Side of Glory. undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - So You Want to be a Dude. 1952 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - The Social Radiator. 1930 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Tamales for Two. undated (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Tangier, the Tactful. undated (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Taos the Unspoiled. 1953 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Ten Things I would not do if I were Married. undated (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Them was the Days. undated (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Then and Now or Ex-Spinster Eats Crow. undated (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - To Souk, to Souk to buy a Fat Scorpion. 1925 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - When I Sailed with the Spanish Fleet. nd, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 48-49)
    - Wellington's Eye. undated (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Western Ways. 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Subseries: Speeches, 1951-1972
    - Book Club. undated (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - Executive Club. 1952 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - General. undated (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Jenny's Class. 1972 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - Literacy Club. 1951 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - New Century Club. 1951 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - Phoenix College. 1951 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - San Diego. 1958 (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - Trinity Presbyterian Church. 1951 (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - Wives of the National Association of Home Builders. 1952 (Box 16, Folder 61)
    - YWCA. 1957 (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - Subseries: Research Files, 1932-1963
    - Adrienne. 1955 (Box 16, Folder 63)
    - England. undated (Box 16, Folder 64)
    - General. undated (Box 16, Folder 65-66)
    - General. undated (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
    - General. 1932-1949 (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
    - General. 1940-1954 (Box 17, Folder 9-11)
    - General. 1950-1963 (Box 17, Folder 12-13)
    - General. 1962 (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - Georgia. undated (Box 17, Folder 16-17)
    - Harem Scare'm. 1948 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Looking Up. 1951-1957 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - . The Memoirs of D'Artagnan 1951-1954 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Ram. undated (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
    - Ram. 1941-1961 (Box 18, Folder 4-9)
    - Ram-Book I. undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Ram-Book III. undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Ram-Book IV. undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Ram-Book V. undated (Box 18, Folder 13-14)
    - Ram-Book VI undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Ram-BookVII undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Ram-BookVIII undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Ram-Book X undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Ram-Character Index. undated (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    - Ram -U.S. History. undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Songs. undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Subseries: Legal Files, 1943-1977
    - Bar Nothing Ranch-Contracts. 1944-1948 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Broadway in a Barn- Contracts. 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Chicken Every Sunday-Contracts. 1943-1977 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Chicken Every Sunday-Copyright. 1971 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Chicken Every Sunday-Royalties. 1944-1956 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Come Clean, My Love-Contracts. 1948-1954 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Eternal Summer-Contracts. 1950 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Footlights and Sixguns-Contracts. 1944 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Ghost Town Bonanza-Contracts. 1953-1954 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Looking Up-Contracts. 1958 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Ram-Contracts. 1958-1963 (Box 19, Folder 163)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow-Contracts. 1943-1944 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow-Contracts. 1949-1966 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow-Copyright. 1971 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Subseries: Publicity Files, 1925-1972
    - Bar Nothing Ranch. 1947-1954 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Broadway in a Barn. 1957 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Chicken Every Sunday. 1943-1965 (Box 19, Folder 22-23)
    - Come Clean, My Love. 1949 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - General. 1925-1972 (Box 19, Folder 25-26)
    - Ghost Town Bonanza. 1954-1956 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Harem Scare'm. 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Looking Up. 1953-1962 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow. 1944 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Ram. 1959-1961 (Box 19, Folder 31-32)
    - Weekly Book Review. 1943-1944 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary-Radio. 1945 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Subseries: Miscellaneous, 1914-1984
    - American Adventures. 1931-1932 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
    - Book Review. 1960 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Chicken Every Sunday-Plates. undated (Box 20, Folder 6-10)
    - Ideas. 1953-1959 (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
    - Illustrations- Bar Nothing Ranch. undated (Box 20, Folder 13-14)
    - Illustrations- Chicken Every Sunday. undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Journal. 1923 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Journal. 1926-1948 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Journal-Europe. 1923-1924 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Journal-Morocco. 1925 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Maid to Order. 1921 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Notes. undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Observations. 1945-1984 (Box 20, Folder 22-23)
    - Poems. undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Right Up Your Street-Television. undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - This is Your Life. 1955 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - The Tucsonian. 1914 (Box 20, Folder 27)
- Series 4: Photographs, Negatives and Slides, 1898-1996
  This series contains photographs, negatives and slides. It is divided into two subseries:
  Business (1929-1954) contains photographs, negatives and slides of John and Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor including professional headshots, images from films and plays of several of Ms. Winchcombe-Taylor's novels and publicity photographs. Also included are photographs of two of Oliver Drachman's businesses.
  Personal (1898-1996) contains photographs of John and Rosemary Winchcombe- Taylor and other members of the Drachman and Winchcombe-Taylor families. Also included are photographs of Alice (West) Drachman's family, the Colliers and Wests. Also included are images of various Drachman residences and Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor's travels in Morocco.
  - Subseries: Business, 1929-1954
    - Photographs Chicken Every Sunday. undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Photographs- Chicken Every Sunday. 1944 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Photographs- Chicken Every Sunday. 1946 (Box 20, Folder 30-31)
    - Photographs-Drachman Fuel Business. undated (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Photographs-Drachman Fuel Business. 1929 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Photographs-Drachman Laundry Business. 1954 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Photographs-General. undated (Box 20, Folder 37-38)
    - Photographs-Looking Up. undated (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1950 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. undated (Box 20, Folder 41-43)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. 1944 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Negatives-Bar Nothing Ranch. undated (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Negatives-Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. undated (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Slides-Chicken Every Sunday, Film. 1948 (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - Slides-Filming, Unidentified. 1949 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - Slides-General. undated (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Slides-76 Ranch. 1947 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Subseries: Personal, 1898-1996
    - Photographs-Collier Family. undated (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Alice West. undated (Box 20, Folder 52-54)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Alice West. 1905-1946 (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Ann Eve. undated (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Anne Rodelle. undated (Box 20, Folder 57)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Anne Rodelle. 1942-1955 (Box 20, Folder 58)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Ethel. undated (Box 20, Folder 59)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Ethel and Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor. undated (Box 20, Folder 60)
    - Photographs-Drachman Family. undated (Box 20, Folder 61-67)
    - Photographs-Drachman Family. undated (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
    - Photographs-Drachman Family. 1938-1967 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Photographs-Drachman Family Residence. undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Photographs-Drachman Family Residence. 1963 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Photographs-Drachman, James Douglas. undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Photographs-Drachman, James Douglas. 1966-1970 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Photographs-Drachman, James West. undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Mose. undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Oliver. undated (Box 21, Folder 11-13)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Oliver. 1903-1946 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Photographs- Drachman, Oliver and Alice. undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Oliver and Alice. 1942-1996 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Oliver and Philip. undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Oliver Residence. undated (Box 21, Folder 18-20)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Oliver Residence. 1958 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Oliver West. undated (Box 21, Folder 23-23)
    - Photographs-Drachman, Philip and Rosa. undated (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Photographs-Gibbons, Floyd. undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Photographs-General. undated (Box 21, Folder 26-30)
    - Photographs-General. 1934-1964 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Photographs-General. 1971 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Photographs-General. 1972-1976 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Photographs-Morocco. undated (Box 21, Folder 34-40)
    - Photographs-West, Alice Amanda I. undated (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Photographs-West, West Family. undated (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Photographs-West, Harry Linden. undated (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Photographs-West, Harry Linden. 1900 (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Photographs-West, Rhoda Collier. undated (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor Family. undated (Box 21, Folder 46-48)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor Family. 1898-1915 (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. undated (Box 21, Folder 50-61)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1914-1915 (Box 21, Folder 62)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1916-1918 (Box 21, Folder 63)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1923-1925 (Box 21, Folder 64)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1928-1929 (Box 21, Folder 65)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1933-1950 (Box 21, Folder 66)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John and Rosemary. undated (Box 21, Folder 67-71)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, John and Rosemary. 1941-1969 (Box 21, Folder 72)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor Residence. undated (Box 21, Folder 73)
    - Photographs-Winchcomeb-Taylor, Rosemary. undated (Box 21, Folder 74-77)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. 1916-1942 (Box 21, Folder 78)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. 1944 (Box 21, Folder 79)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. 1946-1976 (Box 21, Folder 80)
    - Photographs-Winchcombe-Taylor Wedding. 1934 (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - Negatives-Drachman, Ethel. undated (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - Negatives-Drachman, Ethel. 1917 (Box 21, Folder 83)
    - Negatives-General. undated (Box 21, Folder 84)
    - Negatives-Morocco. undated (Box 21, Folder 85-90)
    - Negatives-Morocco. undated (Box 22, Folder 1-3)
    - Negatives-Winchcombe-Taylor Family. undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Negatives-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Negatives-Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Slides-California. 1948 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Slides-CC Party. 1948 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Slides-Drachman, Ethel. 1943 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Slides-Drachman Family Residence. undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Slides-General. undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Slides-Los Angeles. 1943 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Slides-Navajo Reservation. 1949 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Slides-Parade. undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Slides-Ranch. undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Slides-Red Cross First Aid Class. 1957 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Slides-Reservation. undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Slides-Sabino Canyon. undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Slides-Tumacacori. 1947 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Slides-Winchcombe-Taylor Dog. undated (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Slides-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Slides-Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1943-1947 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Slides-Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
- Series VI: Audio-Visual Materials, 1943-1951
  This series (1943-1951) contains records of literary events and music albums.
  - Because. 1948 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Chicken Every Sunday-Review. 1943 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Come Clean, My Love-Interview. 1949 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Come Clean, My Love-Party. 1949 (Box 23, Folder 4-6)
  - Drachman, Frank. undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Sweet Mystery of Life. 1948 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Thine Alone. 1947 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. 1951 (Box 23, Folder 10-14)
- Series V: Scrapbooks, 1903-1996
  This series (1903-1996) contains personal and professional scrapbooks relating to the Drachman family and John and Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor's literary careers. It is divided into two subseries:
  Business (1943-1962) contains scrapbooks of news clippings related to several of John and Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor's novels.
  Personal (1903-1974) contains scrapbooks of news clippings, correspondence and photographs primarily relating to members of the Drachman Family.
  - Subseries: Business, 1943-1962
    - Chicken Every Sunday. 1944-1949 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Come Clean, My Love-Play. 1949 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Ram. 1960-1962 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow. 1940-1945 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary-News Clippings. 1943-1949 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary-News Clippings. 1949-1951 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Subseries: Personal, 1903-1996
    - Drachman, Alice West. 1903-1974 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Drachman, Alice West. 1925-1926 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Drachman, Alice West-Opera Workshop Lecture Series. 1951-1954 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Drachman Family. undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Drachman, Oliver. 1926-1935 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Drachman, Oliver. 1946-1996 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, John-Military. 1939-1941 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Series VII: Oversize Materials, 1902-1981
  This series contains oversize items from various series and subseries including the biographical files, writings series (short stories, research files, publicity files, illustrations) and photographs both business and personal.
  - Biographical Files: Drachman Family-General. 1962 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Files: Drachman Family Tree. 1976 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Files: Drachman Family Tree. 1981 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Files: Winchcombe-Taylor, John-Certificates. 1915-1939 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Files: Winchcombe-Taylor-General. undated (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
  - Writings: Short Stories-American Boy. 1927 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Writings: Short Stories-Boy's Life. 1927-1929 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Writings: Research Files-General. 1940-1949 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Writings: Publicity Files-Chicken Every Sunday. 1949 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Writings: Publicity Files-Looking Up. 1959 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Writings: Publicity Files-Posters: Event undated (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
  - Writings: Miscellaneous-Illustrations: Chicken Every Sunday. undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Writings: Miscellaneous-Illustrations: General. undated (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
  - Writings: Miscellaneous-Illustrations: General. undated (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
  - Writings: Miscellaneous-Illustrations: Ram. undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Writings: Miscellaneous-Illustrations: Ridin' the Rainbow. undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Business-Photographs: Winchcombe- Taylor, Rosemary. undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Drachman, Alice West. undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Drachman, Ann Rodelle. undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Drachman Family. undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Drachman Family. 1910 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Drachman, Oliver. undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Drachman, Oliver. 1925-1932 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Drachman, Oliver and Alice. undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Drachman, Oliver Residences. undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: General. undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Winchcombe-Taylor, John. undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1902-1941 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Winchcombe-Taylor, John and Rosemary. undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Slides: Personal-Photographs: Winchcombe-Taylor, Rosemary. undated (Box 31, Folder 11)